Asalam alaikum and hi to Dr. Asri result
and also our fellow classmates. So for
today our team we present to you about
the comparison between manual life
insurance and also FWD takul. So without
further ado, let's get started. But
before that, I would like to introduce
my teammate friends first, which is the
first one, we have Tashini and then we
do have Norfatin Adila, Norfati, Sufi,
Solea, and the last one is me, myself,
Norad.
So without further ado, let's get
started with the first slide that will
be presented by my other teammates. So
>> I'm going to talk about Manual Life
Insurance. Friend Life Insurance is a
wellestablished international insurance
company with a strong presence in
Malaysia. It offers a wide range of
financial protections and wealth
management products including life
insurance, medical insurance, investment
link plans and also retirement
solutions. Manual life primarily targets
individuals, families and corporate
clients seeking long-term financial
security. As a conventional insurer, its
operations are governed by standard
insurance regulations and are not
subject to Sharia compliance.
For FWD Takaful is a Takaful operator in
Malaysia. It offers Sharia compliant
protection and saving product. FWD
Takaful provides family takaful medical
takaful investment link takaful plans.
The company serves Muslim and also
non-Muslim who prefer ethical and
cooperative financial solution. So all
the products and investment are
supervised by a Sharia commit to ensure
they follow the principles. Next we move
to comparison operating principles
between manual life insurance and FWD
Takapur. For manual life insurance, it
operate based on risk transfer where the
financial financial risk is fully
transferred from the policy holder to
the insurance company. Meanwhile, FWT
takaful operates based on the risk
sharing where participants mutually help
each other through contribution to a
common takaful fund. Furthermore, in
manual life that relationship in a
commercial contract where the
participants pay premiums in exchange
for insurance protection then for the
FWDA cover the operator acts only as a
fund manager while the fund is
collectively owned by the participants
and not the company. Lastly, the
insurance fund is owned by manual life
and any surplus or profit belongs to the
company and its shareholders. In contra
FWD Takaful main objective is a mutual
existence and any surplus after claims
and expenses is share among participants
according to agreed term. Comparative
analysis for investment and sharia
compliance for manual life insurance is
first is conventional investment
principles. Second it's invest in bonds,
equities, interest based instruments and
third its premium owned by insurance.
But for FWD takaful insurance the Sharia
compliance and also the investment is
its Sharia based investment principles.
It invest in suku and Islamic equities
only and its contributions owned by
participants. In terms of profit and
surplus management, manual life
insurance and FWD takaful operate very
differently. Manual generates income
from policy holders premiums and
investment returns where the funds and
profit are fully owned by the company
and its shareholders. Any surplus is not
distributed to policy holders and the
risk is transferred from the policy
holder to the insurer. In contrast, FWD
Takafu earns income mainly through
management fees. The contribution remain
collectively owned by the participants.
Any surplus belongs to the participants
and may be distributed after claims and
expenses. The risk is shared among
participants through the concept of
mult.
>> We talk about the legal and regulatory
between manual life insurance and also
FWD tako. So what's the difference
between these two companies? So the
first one we have for manual life they
regulated under the financial act as
financial services act 2013. Meanwhile
for FWD Takaful they are licensed and
regulated by PNM under the IFSA 2013.
Other than that we can see that manual
life insurance is overseen and is super
supervised by bank naro Malaysia.
Meanwhile for FWD Takaful operates under
a Sharia governance structure so that
they must follow all the shar and so on.
So the last one is manualized must
follow general corporate governance and
compliance requirements. Meanwhile for
FWT tangafu they are subject to specific
taku credential governance rules.
Hi my name is noati mahaz. I'm going to
present about this diagram explain the
provision element in conventional
insurance and how takul avoid them.
Commissioner insurer may involve rebar
because premium are invested in interest
barrier assets GA due the uncertainty in
claim and my as policy holder may lose
premium if no claim is made. In
contrast, Takafu avoid this element by
pulling contribution as tabarus using
clear and transparent contract to reduce
uncertainty and imprising mutual
assistant rather than gambling or profit
driving risk. Our group found that FWD
Takaful stands out for its ethical
principles, surplus sharing and mutual
assistance. However, manual life
insurance has advantage in terms of
product variety and investment
flexibility due to its longer market
presence. Overall, we conclude that both
insurance and takafu play important
roles and the choice depends on
individual needs and values. I will go
to the last part which is how our team
solve a problem. So the first one we
will do a open discussion and clear
communication. So of course before we
start the assignment we will do this one
first and then we will listen to each
member's opinion as we know that every
one have their own opinion. So we need
to know we need to listen every single
of opinion so that we can move to the
another step which is we made a decision
together whether we want to do that or
we want to do that company or so on. So
the last one is we support one another
to ensure the assignment was complete on
time. So we need to help each other if
there's half a person who have a
difficult time to do uh their part or
maybe they talk to do their part
together. So what we all do basically we
discuss all of this in our WhatsApp
group so that we can help each other.
Next, this is how we going to solve our
problem during group assignment such as
disagreement or delay. We resolve
through the open discussion and clear
communication. The team listen to each
other opinion and made decision
together. When challenge happened, task
were adjusted and members support each
other to ensure the assignment was
complete on time.
>> So that's all from our group. Thank you.